Preliminary Guide to the Marine Laboratory Records, 1931-2006 UA.18.03.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marine Laboratory records
1931-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Marine Laboratory
UA.18.03.0001
106 Linear Feet
The Duke University Marine Laboratory, founded in 1938, educates undergraduate and graduate students in the marine sciences. Part of the Nicholas School of the Environment, the Beaufort, North Carolina laboratory is also a renowned center of scientific research. The Marine Laboratory Records include photographs, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, recommendations, and reports documenting the Laboratory's work and administration. Major subjects include marine biology, oceanography, and zoology; research and study of the marine sciences; the Marine Biomedical Center; oceanic research vessels including the Monitor; and John D. Costlow, the director of the Laboratory for many years.
Access Restrictions
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Provenance
The Marine Laboratory Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1970 (A70-70), 1977 (A77-47, A77-106), 1988 (A88-0055), 1993 (A93-19, A93-120), and 2018 (UA2018.0075. UA2018.0080, UA2018.0085).
Historical Note
The Duke University Marine Laboratory began in 1938. Its original founders, Dr. A.S. Pearse advocated for this coastal laboratory space and succeeded in securing Pivers Island in Beaufort, North Carolina for this purpose. Beginning as a summer research facility, the Marine Laboratory has grown into a year-round center for research and training of undergraduates, graduate students, scientists, and other guests from around the world.
The Marine Laboratory is a campus of Duke University, and operates within the Nicholas School of the Environment. According the Marine Laboratory's website (http://www.env.duke.edu/marinelab), approximately 3500 people visit or research the Marine Laboratory annually. The faculty focus on a diverse set of disciplines, including "oceanography, marine biology, marine biomedicine, marine biotechnology, and coastal marine policy and management."
Collection Overview
The Marine Laboratory Records include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, recommendations, and reports documenting the Laboratory's work and administration. Much of the material focuses on student and faculty research in Beaufort, North Carolina. There are also extensive correspondence and subject files belonging to John Costlow, Director of the Marine Laboratory. The collection also includes personal information on students, faculty, and staff, and these files are restricted under FERPA.
Accessions from 2018 include extensive photographs, including prints and slides, as well as administrative materials, reports, curriculur materials, and others.
Related Archival Materials note
The Origin and First Thirty-Five Years of Duke University Marine Laboratory by Cazlyn G. Bookhout, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Arthur Sperry Pearse Papers, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Irving Emery Gray Papers, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Conditions Governing Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Conditions Governing Access
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is unprocessed and may require screening, arrangement, and/or rehousing before use.
Zoology -- North Carolina; Oceanography -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- North Carolina -- Beaufort; Research -- North Carolina; Marine biology; Beaufort (N.C.); Oceanography; Marine biology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- North Carolina -- Beaufort; Duke University. Department of Zoology; Costlow, John D., 1927-; Duke University. Marine Biomedical Center; Duke University. Marine Laboratory -- History; Duke University. Marine Laboratory; Monitor (Ironclad); Bookhout, Cazlyn Greer, 1907-
- Accession Number A77-47
  - Contract and Specifications for Work on Boat, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Cooperative Research and Training Program in Biological Oceanography, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Specifications of Boat, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Boat Plans and Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Plans for Boat, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Plans for Boat and Blueprints, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Robert Menzies, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence on Oceanographic Program Directorship, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Oceanography Program, 1960 (Box 1)
  - John Ruther, 1961 (Box 1)
  - National Science Foundation Pre- and Post-Doctoral Award Grant, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Robert Menzies, 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - Boat Committee, 1960-1961, [2 folders] (Box 1)
  - Applications for Program Director in Oceanography and Physical Oceanographer (Box 1)
  - Proposal - NSF Oceanographic Vessel Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1)
  - DUML and "Eastward" News and Publicity, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - DUML - Currents, June 1978-August 1979 (Box 1)
  - Director's Reports and General Proposals, 1954-1965 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, Bulletins, Pamphlets, 1963-1978 (Box 1)
  - Oak Ridge Radiation Course, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Manual for Use of R/V Eastward, September 1968 (Box 1)
  - Oak Ridge Radiation Course, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Drs. Wilbur and Hollander Radiation Biology Course, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Radiation Biology for High School Teachers, 1957, [2 folders] (Box 1)
  - Bulletin DU Marine Lab, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Bulletins-NSF Awards, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Dining Hall - Martha Willett, 1957 (Box 2)
  - DUML Library, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Cost of Future Expansion, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 2)
  - Job Applications, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Gray and Broad - Bottom Survey Proposal, 1957 (Box 2)
  - NSF Scholarships, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Printed Matter - NSF, 1957 (Box 2)
  - NSF Scholarship Proposal, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Publicity and Public Relations, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Recreation Fund, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Reprints Exchange Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Suggested Equipment for Beaufort, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Zoology 2 Orders, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Award Report, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Award Applicants - Predoctoral NSF, 1957 (Box 2)
  - AIBS Article, Announcement, and Letters, 1954-1957 (Box 2)
  - DU Marine Lab - NIH Proposal, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Bulletins - DU Marine Lab, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence relative to petty cash - C.R. Duval, 1954-1956 (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Beaufort Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Marine Invertebrate Zoology, 1955 (Box 2)
  - DU Marine Lab Publicity, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Bulletins - DU Marine Lab, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Purchasing Agent, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - National Science Proposal Scholarship and Reports, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - William A. Ellison, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Shrimp Proposal - Fish and Wildlife, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Publicity and Public Relations, 1955 (Box 2)
  - NSF Scholarship Program, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Award Report, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Bulletins - DU Marine Lab, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Institutional Exchange Lists, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Publicity and Public Relations, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
  - War Surplus Life Boat, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Naval Architects and Shipbuilders - W.K. Howard, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Research Triangle Institute, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Simpson and Associates, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Grant Proposal, February 1961 (Box 3)
  - Great Lakes College Association Students Training Program in Marine Biology, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
  - Great Lakes Student Training Program in Marine Biology II, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Movie Scripts, Beaufort, 1953-1960 (Box 3)
  - Scholarships, Beaufort, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Duke Marine Lab Bulletins, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Byson Legal Release, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Duke Marine Lab Bulletins, 1952 (Box 3)
  - John Costlow, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Publicity and Public Relations, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Southern Regional Marine Science Programs, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Scholarships, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Clinton Atkinson, 1949-1952 (Box 3)
  - Beaufort Budget, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Malcolm Reid, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Requests for Use of Marine Laboratory Facilities, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Henry Kritzler, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
  - Letters to and from Dr. Humm, 1946-1948 (Box 3)
  - Duke Marine Laboratory Bulletins, 1944-1951 (Box 3)
  - Budget Data, 1947-1949 (Box 3)
  - DUML, 1946-1948 (Box 3)
  - Publicity and Plans, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Publicity and Plans, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Plans, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Plans and Supplies - Correspondence with Holton, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Plans and Supplies, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Plans and Supplies, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Plans, 1935 (Box 3)
  - General, Course, and Seminar Descriptions, 1965, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Currents, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1969, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - Ten-year Projection for DUML Presented to Long Range Planning Committee, January 1961 (Box 3)
  - [Bulletins, Publications, and Clippings], 1945-1980 (Box 3)
  - Marine Laboratory (Beaufort, NC) [Clippings] 1981-1987 (Box 3)
  - Marine Laboratory [Clippings], 1981-1984 (Box 3)
  - DUML Newsletter, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - [Reports, Schedules, and Bulletins], 1965-1967 (Box 3)
  - R/V Cape Hatteras Dedication, 1981 (Box 3)
  - R/V Cape Hatteras - Important Documents, 1954-1957 (Box 3)
  - [ Currents and clippings], 1970-1975 (Box 3)
  - Reports and Bulletins
    - A Proposal for the Development of Duke University Marine Laboratory, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Director's Annual Report
      - June 1960-June 1961 (Box 4)
      - 1961-1963 (Box 4)
      - June 1, 1964-August 31, 1965 (Box 4)
      - September 1, 1965-August 31, 1966 (Box 4)
      - September 1, 1966-August 31, 1967 (Box 4)
      - September 1, 1967-August 31, 1968 (Box 4)
      - September 1, 1968-August 31, 1969 (Box 4)
      - September 1, 1969-August 31, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Progress Reports
      - 1964-1965 (Box 4)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 4)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 4)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 4)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 4)
      - 1969-1970, [2 volumes] (Box 4)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 4)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 4)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 4)
      - 1975 (Box 4)
      - 1976 (Box 4)
    - Bulletins
      - January 1965 (Box 4)
      - January 1966 (Box 4)
      - November 1966 (Box 4)
      - November 1968 (Box 4)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Marine Littoral Diatoms of Beaufort, North Carolina January 1965 (Box 4)
    - Duke University Marine Laboratory (Box 4)
    - Duke University Marine Laboratory, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Research Vessel Eastward: Fifteen Years of Service, 1978 (Box 4)
- Accession Number A79-53
  - Marine Biomedical Center
    - Progress/Annual Reports 1979-1985 (Box 4)
    - Environs (Newsletter) 1978-1988, [2 folders] (Box 4)
- Accession Number A88-0055
  - Correspondence
    - California USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Connecticut USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Delaware USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Florida USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Georgia USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Hawaii USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Illinois USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Kansas USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Louisiana USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Maine USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Maryland USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Massachusetts USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Michigan USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - New Hampshire USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - New Jersey USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - New York USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - North Carolina USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Oregon USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Pennsylvania USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Rhode Island USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Tennessee USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Texas USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Vermont USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Virginia USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Washington USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Washington DC, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Wisconsin USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - Misc. USA, 1966- (Box 5)
    - December 1969 (Box 5)
    - November 1969 (Box 5)
    - October 1969 (Box 5)
    - September 1969 (Box 5)
    - August 1969 (Box 5)
    - July 1969 (Box 5)
    - June 1969 (Box 5)
    - May 1969 (Box 5)
    - April 1969 (Box 5)
    - March 1969 (Box 5)
    - February 1969 (Box 5)
    - January 1969 (Box 5)
    - December 1968 (Box 5)
    - November 1968 (Box 5)
    - October 1968 (Box 5)
    - September 1968 (Box 5)
    - August 1968 (Box 5)
    - July 1968 (Box 5)
    - June 1968 (Box 5)
    - May 1968 (Box 5)
    - April 1968 (Box 5)
    - March 1968 (Box 6)
    - February 1968 (Box 6)
    - January 1968 (Box 6)
  - Questionnaire - Long Range Plans, October 1964 (Box 6)
  - Ten Year Projection for Duke University Marine Lab, October 1964 (Box 6)
  - Director's Report [correspondence and other materials], 1964 (Box 6)
  - Director's Report [correspondence and other materials], 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Annual Report [correspondence and other materials], 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - [Evaluation of NSF Expansion], 1980 (Box 6)
  - NSF Proposal - Development of the Duke University Marine Laboratory, 1966 (Box 6)
  - NSF Site Visit, 1966 (Box 6)
  - National Institute of Health Memos, Correspondence, etc., 1961 (Box 6)
  - Congress and Marine Biology, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Gifts, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Educational Facilities Committee, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Name of Buildings Concerning Blomquist and Sandeen, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Associated Colleges of the Midwest (Box 6)
  - DML Posters (Box 6)
  - University Planning Committee (Box 6)
  - Grounds - Landscaping, etc., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Annual Report of the Division of Biological and Medical Sciences, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Personnel in Residence, Fall 1964 (Box 6)
  - Preliminary Examinations - Bookhout, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Policy Matters, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - President's Visit, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Division of Commercial Fisheries, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Marine Biology and Ecology and Biological Oceanography - Proposal, Bureau of Comm. Fisheries Ed. Grant, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Training Program in Marine Biology (Box 6)
  - Marine Geology, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Laboratory Space, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Legislation - Oceanography, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Research Space, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Equipment - Duke Marine Laboratory, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Program for Stipends for Research Training in Marine Biology, Paleontology, and Systematic Zoology (Box 6)
  - Engineering, College of (Duke), 1965 (Box 6)
  - Pier-DUML, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Oceanography, NAS Committee on, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Deepstar Systems Marketing, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Neptune, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Research Space, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Univ. of NC Water Resources Research Institute - David Howells, 1966 (Box 6)
  - US National Museum, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Student-Faculty-Administration Committee, Dr. T.W. Johnson, Chairman, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Services - Laboratory (Box 6)
  - Storage Building, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Storeroom - DUML (Box 6)
  - Symposium Committee, Duke University, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Summer Session Statistical Report on Enrollment, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Staff Meetings, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Serials Available at Bureau of Comm Fisheries, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Sea Grant Colleges, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Staffs - Botany and Zoology, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Town's People, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Classified Information (Box 6)
  - Duke Endowment Research Proposal - Costlow, 1966 (Box 6)
  - NASA, 1966 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Senate - Water Pollution, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Marine Science Program at Duke University (Box 6)
  - Guest Lectures, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences - Dean Bowman, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Graduate School, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Program in Marine Biology (Box 7)
  - National Science Foundation Environmental Biology Program, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Visiting Investigators, 1966-1967 (Box 7)
  - Visiting Classes, 1966-1969 (Box 7)
  - Sigma Xi, 1966-1967 (Box 7)
  - Publicity, 1964-1967 (Box 7)
  - Semi-Annual Report DUML, April 3, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Property - Beaufort, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Personnel DUML, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Users Conference, Washington D.C., 1967 (Box 7)
  - Semi-Annual Report, April 3, 1967 (Box 7)
  - University of North Carolina Institute of Fisheries Research (Box 7)
  - UV Unites - Dr. Bookhout, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Mark Etheridge Fellowships, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Notices (Box 7)
  - Symposium - Houston, Texas - Dr. Bookhout, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Data Processing, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Duke Endowment, 1962-1967 (Box 7)
  - DUML Staff Meetings - Non Academic, 1967 (Box 7)
  - ESSA, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Executive Committee of Graduate Faculty, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Zoology Department Notices, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Graduate School Information, 1967 (Box 7)
  - DUML Notices, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Memos, 1963-1968 (Box 7)
  - Marine Sciences, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Training in Marine Sciences, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Zoology Staff Meetings, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Zoology - General Correspondence, January 1968 (Box 7)
  - Zoology Majors' Visit, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Granting Agencies (Box 7)
  - Notices - Duke University (Box 7)
  - Duke University - Summary of On-Going Marine-Related Activities, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Marine Microbiology Course (Advisory Committee) (Box 7)
  - Biochemists Visit, October 1969 (Box 7)
  - Zoology Department Notices (Box 7)
  - Research Space Correspondence, Summer 1969 (Box 7)
  - Visiting Classes, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Visiting Investigators, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Visitors, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Visitors, 1963-1969 (Box 7)
  - Zoology Majors Spring, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Student Weekend, Fall 1969 (Box 7)
  - Executive Committee - Duke Marine Lab Correspondence, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Minutes of Executive Committee, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Executive Committee Visit - Duke University, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Duke University Executive Committee, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Advisory Committee
    - 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - 1965 (Box 7)
    - 1966 (Box 7)
    - 1966-1967, [2 folders] (Box 7)
    - 1967 (Box 7)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 7)
    - 1968-1969, [2 folders] (Box 7)
  - [Correspondence]
    - January 1977 (Box 8)
    - February 1977 (Box 8)
    - March 1977, [2 folders] (Box 8)
    - April 1977 (Box 8)
    - May 1977 (Box 8)
    - June 1977 (Box 8)
    - July 1977 (Box 8)
    - August 1977, [2 folders] (Box 8)
    - September 1977 (Box 8)
    - October 1977 (Box 8)
    - November 1977 (Box 8)
    - December 1977 (Box 8)
  - Subject Files
    Scope and Contents note
    The Subject Files date from John Costlow's directorship of DUML. Many of these files are restricted by FERPA and employee privacy restrictions. Please consult an archivist about use of these files.
    - Abd-El-Meneen, Mahmoud Ahmed (Egypt) Participant ETP, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Academic Paper, Making the Most of Faculty Leadership, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Accommodations at Universities throughout Great Britain (Box 8)
    - Academic Press, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - Akesson, Bertil
      - (Sweden) (Box 8)
      - Ophryotrocha diadema MS, 1977 (Box 8)
      - Manuscript on Dinophilus (Box 8)
    - Aleem, Prof. A. A. (Saudi Arabia) sabbatical (Box 8)
    - Allison, Ms. Sandra (Box 8)
    - Alma College, Alma Michigan (Box 8)
    - Alpha Helix
      - 1978 (Box 8)
      - Documents, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
      - Documents, 1976 (Box 8)
      - Program (Box 8)
      - Review Committee, May 2, 1977-May 3, 1977 (Box 8)
      - Review Meeting, April 1978 (Box 8)
    - Al-Saadi, Dr. Hussain A., Univ. of Basrah, Iraq (Box 8)
    - American Freedom Association Ocean Education Project (Box 8)
    - American Geophysical Union (Box 8)
    - American Naturalist (Box 8)
    - American Society of Limnology and Oceanography (Box 8)
    - Anderson, Dr. Jack, 1971-1975 (Box 8)
    - Andryszak, Mr. Bryan (LSU), 1977-1979 (Box 8)
    - US Army Corps of Engineers, 1972-1976 (Box 8)
    - US Army Corps of Engineers, 1974-1979 (Box 9)
    - Ashy, Dr. M.A., 1979 (Box 9)
    - Auditorium, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Audiovisual, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - B Miscellaneous, 1977-1979 (Box 9)
    - Baier, Rodger W. (Dr.) Tenure, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Baier, Dr. Rodger (Box 9)
    - Bamstedt, Ulf (Box 9)
    - Barmeier, Judy (Box 9)
    - Bastress, Mr. Sue, 1974-1978 (Box 9)
    - Battaglia, Bruno (Italy) (Box 9)
    - Baxter, Diane (Grad Student), 1978 (Box 9)
    - Baxter, Diane A., Oral Prelim Paper on Littorina irrorata (Box 9)
    - Baxter Laboratories (Box 9)
    - Bebbington, Peter M., Staffordshire, England (Box 9)
    - Benijts Claus, Christine and Frank (Belgium), 1974-1976 (Box 9)
    - Mary Berry Thesis - Final Draft (Box 9)
    - Betz, Frederick S. - EPA, Washington, 1977-1979 (Box 9)
    - Bilio, Dr. Martin, Italy, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
    - Biochemistry Retreat, September 21, 1978-September 24, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Biological Sciences Council, 1968-1977 (Box 9)
    - Mary Bisson - NATO proposal (Box 9)
    - Bisson, Mary, Physiology - John Gutknecht's lab (Box 9)
    - Bjorklund, Dr. Kjell R. (Norway (Box 9)
    - Bjorn-Rasmussen, Mrs. S. (Sweden) (Box 9)
    - Duke University Office of Black Affairs (Box 9)
    - Blackburn, Dr. John O. (Box 9)
    - Blankley, Dr. William (Box 9)
    - Bouhalila, Mr. Ridha (Tunisia) (Box 9)
    - Bousquette, George D., 1979 (possible grad) (Box 9)
    - Brattstrom, Professor Hans (Norway) (Box 9)
    - Brauer, Dr. Ralph (Box 9)
    - Brawley, Susan H. candidatee for Botany post at Marine Lab), 1978 (Box 9)
    - Bretz, Dr. Bill (Box 9)
    - Bronk, Dr. Detlev (Box 9)
    - Brooks, Curtis (student), Spring 1975 (Box 9)
    - Brummett, Dr. Anna Ruth (Box 9)
    - Bamstedt, Ulf (Box 9)
    - Burdon-Jones, Cyril (Australia (Box 9)
    - Bwathondi, Philip O.J. (1977 ITPMS participant) (Box 9)
    - Byrne, Dr. John B. (Box 9)
    - C Miscellaneous, 1976-1979, [2 folders] (Box 9)
    - Calabrese, Dr. Anthony (Box 9)
    - Caldwell, Richard (Box 9)
    - Calendar, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - Calendar of Events, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
    - Duke University Campus Club Lecture, January 1979 (Box 9)
    - Canadian Journal of Zoology (Box 9)
    - Capsules (Capsulated Systems, Inc.) (Box 9)
    - Carcinological Society (proposed) - Manning at Smithsonian (Box 9)
    - Carpenter, John F. (1977 spring term student) (Box 9)
    - Case Existological Labs, Inc. (Box 9)
    - Castello, Hugo (Argentina) (Box 9)
    - Castello, Dr. Jorge Pablo (Brazil (Box 9)
    - CENMARR (through John B. Lewis, McGill Univ., Redpath Museum) (Box 9)
    - Center for Natural Areas (Box 9)
    - Center for Ocean Management Studies (Box 9)
    - Cerame-Vivas, Max (Puerto Rico) (Box 9)
    - Charniaux-Cotton, Helene (France) (Box 9)
    - Prof. Eric Charnov, Univ. of Utah (Box 9)
    - Cheney, Dr. Peter, Dir NC Dept Science and Technology, RTP, NC (Box 9)
    - Chesapeake Science (Box 9)
    - Chughtai, Mr. Iffat (Pakistan) (Box 9)
    - Cimberg, Robert L., Univ. California Irvine, Dept. Ecol. Evol. Biol. (Box 9)
    - Cleaveland, Dr. Frederick (Box 9)
    - US Coast Guard, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Coll, Javier (Box 9)
    - Carpenter, John F. (1977 spring term student) (Box 9)
    - Commito, Dr. John A. (Box 9)
    - Commito, John Angelo - John Sutherland Graduate Stud. (Box 9)
    - Commonwealth Fund through Zoology Department (Box 9)
    - Computer Analysis/Data Handling Program - Robert E. Fritz (Box 9)
    - Connect - UNESCO (Box 9)
    - Conte, Dr. Frank (Box 9)
    - Office of Continuing Medical Educ. Mid-Summer Program, Atlantic Beach (Box 9)
    - Cooper-Willis, Dr. A. (Box 9)
    - Corkett, Dr. Christopher Dalhousie (Box 9)